https://raft.ac.uk/privacy-policy-2/

Skip to content
Home
About Raft
Our History Our Vision, Mission, and Values Our Impact RAFT Team
Our Staff Patrons Trustees Scientific Committee
Research
Research Projects
Breast reconstruction Bone regeneration 3D Printing Keloid Scar
Research Strategy Commercialisation Research Partners
Resources
Published papers Research Posters
Get Involved
Fundraise for RAFT Corporate giving Education opportunities How we spend your money
News
X
DONATE
Privacy Policy
Help us keep developing Pioneering treatments to restore patients’ quality of life that have suffered physical trauma.
Policy Statement
RAFT is a charity registered in the UK, charity number 299811. At RAFT we take your privacy very seriously and are committed to protecting your personal information.This policy explains how we and our affiliated subsidiaries, RAFT Enterprises Ltd, RAFT Ventures Ltd and Smart Matrix Intellectual Property Ltd, may collect and use the information you give us.You can contact us at: E-mail charity@raft.ac.uk
RAFT's Promise
We will always store your personal details securelyWe will only hold your information for as long as necessaryWe will tell you how we are using information about you; and when you ask us to stop using your data, we will do so promptlyWe will only contact you in the ways you wish, using what you have told us to help communicate better with you
This policy includes
How we collect informationWhat personal information we collectHow we use your personal informationWhat we do to keep your information safe and who has access to itHow we keep your information up to dateHow long we keep your information forYour right to your information
How we collect your information
We collect information you provide when you:Donate to usTelephone us, e-mail us, text us or visit our website and enquire about our activitiesPost content on our social media sitesSign up to receive updates on a campaign or on our activities generallyAttend a meeting with us and provide us with information about youTake part in one of our events or fundraise on our behalfVolunteer for usWe may also receive information about you from third-parties; but only if you have given them permission to share your information. Examples of this are if you are fundraising for us via Just Giving, MyDonate or Virgin Money, or if you post about RAFT on Facebook, Twitter or other social media services. You can refer to the Privacy Policy of these organisations to understand how they will share information with RAFT.
What personal information we collect
The type and quantity of information we collect and how we use it depends on why you have provided it. Some information is legally required, notably details to support a Gift Aid claim.Most personal information you provide to RAFT is collected because you have consented for RAFT to have this information. It enables RAFT to thank you for your support and to communicate with you the progress and plans of RAFT’s world-class medical research and the benefits it delivers to patients.If you support us as a donor, fundraiser, event participant, advocate, we will collect where relevant:Your full nameYour contact details, namely full address, phone numbers, e-mailYour contact preferencesYour date of birthYour bank detailsYour credit card details (only until we have been able to process the transaction)Details of donations you have made, RAFT events you have attended, specific areas of RAFT’s work that you are interested inInformation about you that may help us ensure our communication to you is relevant and tailored. This could include information from third party sources about your interests such as shopping preferences, hobbies, professional body memberships
Childrens Data
We do not actively collect information from children under 16. If we have supporters who are under 16, we will ask a parent or guardian for consent to collect information about children.
How we use your personal information
We use your personal information in a number of ways, including:To administer your donation, including Gift Aid processingTo update you about the progress of the research you are supporting and our fundraising campaignsTo help make requests for donations that are tailored to your preferences, interests and other characteristicsTo invite you to participate in fundraising, voluntary surveys, advocacyTo maintain our organisational records and ensure that we have the most up to date preferences on how you wish us to contact youTo display your profile on our website and social media if you have agreed that we can do so, for instance as an advocate or fundraiserTo help us improve our campaigns and the information services we provide to donors, other supporters and advocatesTo analyse and improve our website and social media servicesTo analyse your website behaviourTo help us work with third parties to ensure we send you targeted communications that are in accordance with the consents you have given
What we do to keep your information safe and who has access to it
We place great importance on the security of your personal information and will always try to take appropriate precautions to protect it.We establish our online sites with the industry-recommended security features and carry out regular security reviews and investigations of any potential breaches.We ensure that only authorised RAFT staff and contractors have access to your information and that they are appropriately trained to manage your data.Despite all our precautions, no data can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of information you disclose to us online, and you must understand that you do so at your own risk. However, any payment card details entered into our website are passed securely and directly to our payment processing providers who meet Payment Card Industry (PCI) security standards.We do use external organisations to process personal data on our behalf. When engaging a contractor company we check that they meet all relevant regulations and registrations. We also include in the contract the data protection obligations to give maximum protection of your personal information. We may legally be required to disclose your personal information to the police or for other regulatory reasons in certain circumstances. In other circumstances, we will only ever share your personal information if we have your consent to do so.
How we keep our information up to date
We aim to be in contact with our supporters at least once a year and we will update any changes notified promptly.You can write to us, e-mail us or call us with any changes.From time to time, we may use databases such as the Post Office’s National Change of Address register to update our records.
How long we keep your information for
We will hold your personal information on our database on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity. For instance, we will keep a record of donations you have made for at least six years. We would usually remove the records of a donor who has not donated for the past ten years.If you ask us to stop sending you marketing materials and newsletters, we will keep a record of your contact details and preferences to enable us to comply with the request not to contact you.
Your right to your information
We collect and store your personal information so that RAFT can communicate with its supporters, seek donations, thank donors and keep all supporters updated on its valuable scientific research.Although in most cases we will seek consent to process your personal information, we may in some instances process your information without consent when we are legally allowed to do so. This will only be where it is in our legitimate interests to do so and where we are confident that this processing is not likely to prejudice your legitimate interests or rights and freedoms.Where we are processing your personal information based on consent that you have given us, you are entitled to withdraw that consent. You have the right to ask us to stop processing your personal information at any time, subject to us having a legal obligation to retain certain information, for instance for audit.You have the right to request a copy of the information we hold about you, a Subject Access Request (SAR). Our contact details are at the top of this privacy policy.If the information is incorrect or you disagree with it, you have the right to ask us to correct it or erase it. We will promptly correct any inaccuracies and discuss with you any other changes you request.For more information on these rights please read the relevant guidance issued by the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at:https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/is-my-information-being-handled-correctly/If you would like to make a complaint about how we process your personal data, please contact our Data Protection Officer, details above.If you are not satisfied with how your complaint is dealt with, you should contact the Information Commissioner’s Office (www.ico.org.uk). Alternatively, you are entitled to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office without first referring your complaint to us.
Our use of cookies
Cookies are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enable the server to collect information from the browser. The cookie then sits as a small text file on your computer’s hard drive and identifies you to the web server when you return to that website in the future. For RAFT’s website, like most websites, this helps us serve you better by already knowing which pages you have seen before and are interested in.
×
